Guide to the Joe Long Oral History Collection AIA.070
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Joe Long Oral History Collection
2011-2012
AIA.070
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
0.25 linear feet in 1 manuscript box
Joseph Long (1952- ) is the son of Irish immigrant parents from Arklow, Co. Wicklow and grew up in Manhattan's Chelsea neighborhood. He has a Master's Degree in Irish and Irish-American Studies from Glucksman Ireland House, New York University, during which time he conducted the 11 interviews that comprise this collection. The interviews were conducted with several Irish Americans on the subject of growing up in New York City’s Chelsea and West Village neighborhoods and focus on similar topics and themes, including educational institutions, the family structures typical of the neighborhoods, the ethnic and social composition of the neighborhoods, and sports and leisure (often associated with Greenwich House). Another recurring subject is the intersection of ethnicity, labor industries, and social interactions, with specific emphasis on the longshoremen of the Chelsea Piers.
Long, Joe, 1952-
Arrangement
Interviews are arranged alphabetically by interviewee’s last name.
Historical/Biographical Note
Joe Long (1952- ) is the son of Irish immigrant parents from Arklow, Co. Wicklow and grew up in Manhattan's Chelsea neighborhood. He spent his career in management with United Technologies and Otis Elevator. He has a Master's Degree in Irish and Irish-American Studies from Glucksman Ireland House, New York University.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The oral history interviews in this collection were created in the course of Joe Long’s academic work in the Irish and Irish-American Studies Master’s program from Glucksman Ireland House at New York University. The interviews, along with supplemental materials from the project, were transferred to the Archives of Irish America at Tamiment Library in June 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.163.
Related Archival Materials
Ireland House Oral History Collection (AIA 030)
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of 11 oral history interviews conducted by Joe Long in 2011 and 2012 with several Irish Americans on the subject of growing up in New York City’s Chelsea and West Village neighborhoods. Many interviews discuss similar topics and themes, including educational institutions, the family structures typical of the neighborhoods, the ethnic and social composition of the neighborhoods, and sports and leisure (often associated with Greenwich House). Another recurring subject is the intersection of ethnicity, labor industries, working conditions, and social interactions, with specific emphasis on the longshoremen of the Chelsea Piers. Several interview subjects discuss their professional careers, including police work, military service, and modeling. Some interviews are accompanied by a partial transcript of the conversation.
Chelsea Piers (New York, N.Y.); Ethnic neighborhoods; Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Irish Americans |x Ethnic identity.; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |x Social life and customs.; Stevedores |z New York (State) |z New York |v Interviews.
- Brennan, Eddie, Feb 8, 2012, Feb 11, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Caffrey, Jeanne, Jan 7, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dean, Joe, Feb 12, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- English, Peter, Oct 16, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Gibson, Bob, Jan 15, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Harper Pezzella, Susan, Oct 27, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Kelly, Tom, Jan 14, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- O'Brien, Frank, Nov 26, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Shea, Artie, Nov 6, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sullivan, Brian, Feb 11, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Woods, Mary, Jan 17, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 11)